KHAJA FURKHAN AHMED (1) Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Project Management, Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, System Administration, Category Management, Strategic Planning, Risk Analysis, Project Management, Agile Methodology, HTML, CSS, PHP, iQuery.



Current Designation: PHP Developer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Extreme agile private limited Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical and Electronics]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Developer, Project Management, Software Development, Application Programming, Web

Development, System Administration, Category Management, Strategic Planning, Risk Analysis, Project Management, Agile

Methodology,HTML,CSS,PHP,jQuery

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

B.E in Electrical and Electronics from JNTU College, Hyderabad passed out in 2012. 2 years? experience as Electrical Engineer and 5 years? experience as Web Developer. Specialized in web based and mobile applications design & development. Excellence in co-ordination with various departments, negotiations & other post order activities. Quality-oriented professional with excellent communication, problem solving & team building skills.

Work Experience

Extreme agile private limited as PHP Developer

Mar 2015 to Till Date

As PHP Developer i am responsible for creating and implementing an array of Web-based products using PHP, MySQL, Ajax, and JavaScript. I develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and assist frontend developers by ensuring their work integrates with the application.

SABIC as Electrical Engineer

Feb 2015 to Jan 2016

Projects: I. Metallurgical Corporation of China (MCC) JCSSC, as QA/QC Electrical Engineer. July 2015 - January 2016 Main Responsibilities:

- * Document Review of Quality Procedures, Quality Control Plan, Method of Statements, ITP and Scope of work.
- * Quality Inspection of Electrical Equipment/Materials, Receiving, Installation, Testing, Pre-commissioning & Commissioning of Power Systems
- * Installation and Inspection of -

Low Voltage Cables (Power, Control & Instrumentation) MV/HV Cables (380kv) using Direct Buried Cable & Conduit Trenches, Above Grade Conduits and Cable Trays from Source to Load.

ISO Phase Bus Ducts (IPBD), High Potential Testing of IPBD Connecting to HV Transformers and Generators. Witness the High Potential Withstand Test for MV and HV (380kv) cables / Cable Bus in Accordance with Standard Procedures and Safety Precautions.

Winteness the Pre-commissioning Tests of Lighting Panel, Power Panel Boards, LV Switch Boards (Non-Industrial Purposes) LV Motor Control Centers (MCC) and LV/MV Switchgears

Transformers, GSU (Generator step-up transformer 18/380 KV), Auxiliary Transformers, Liquid Filled and Dry Type

Transformers.

Earthing Installation and Pre-commissioning for all Electical Equipments, Systems and Structures, Ground Grid, Pit & Well, Ground Grid to Equipment, System and Structures, Gates and Fence connections, Resistance Resting and Torque Testing. Bonding for Direct Buried Conduits

- * Preparing all Checklist, Test Report and Pre-Commissioning Packagaes as per Project Requirement.
- TPC E LEARNING SERVICES, as Electrical Engineer February 2015 July 2015 Job Responsibilities: *

Troubleshooting the Breakdown Problems with I - schematic tool with proper Electrical Drawings.

- * Co-ordinating with Hadeed SMEs in terms of collecting Electrical Drawing for the PLC and Substation Equipment's like MCC Switch gear and transformers.
- * Carrying out Quality analysis process on the Electrical Drawings.
- * Liaising with client departments, and other engineering production colleagues.
- * Co-ordinating with engineering design personnel to produce as built drawings.
- * Supervise and train project team members as necessary.
- * Potential to work in challenging and pressure environmental conditions.
- * Working with special equipment's such as Programmable logic controller (PLC) which controls the Hydraulic and pneumatic systems.

VIJAY NIRMAN PVT LIMITED. as Electrical Engineer

Mar 2013 to Dec 2014

Job Responsibilities:

- * Checking material submittal & shop drawing submittal as per specification.
- * Ensure proper & effective co ordination with client and contractors' suppliers in connection with quality matters
- * Checking of works, monitoring sub-contractor progress.
- * Conducting weekly meeting with subcontractors and clients regarding project status, and completion and safety construction management.
- * Preparation of shop drawings, as built drawings.
- * QA/QC monitoring, preparing checklist, project scheduling.
- * Commissioning of the project and effectively solving snag issues.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical and Electronics) from intu college in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
PHP, HTML5, JavaScript, J Query	
JAVA	
RED HAT	
MS OFFICE	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Urdu				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent $1/22/2021 \hspace{1.5cm} \text{https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=09bd1cd5fce59457de7392bf557d10415a0808074f1b0a19031241505a...} \\$

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time